(Live) Public Speech at UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn
(En vivo) Discurso público en la Conferencia de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Cambio Climático en Bonn (Live) Public Speech at UN Climate Change Conference in Bonn
Welcome to today's session (Moderator Dr. Xu)
Bienvenidos a la sesión de hoy (Moderador Dr. Xu) Welcome to today's session (Moderator Dr. Xu)
So on the topic of Chinese energy transition and technology innovation, we
Entonces, sobre el tema de la transición energética china y la innovación tecnológica, So on the topic of Chinese energy transition and technology innovation,
find ourselves like in the middle of an era where both the
nos encontramos en el centro de una era donde tanto la urgencia de luchar contra el cambio climático we find ourselves like in the middle of an era where both the
urgency of combating climate change and the need for technology advancements.
y la necesidad de avances tecnológicos son urgentes. urgency of combating climate change and the need for technology advancements.
So China stands in the forefront of this challenge due to huge
China está en la primera línea de este desafío debido a su gran población So China stands in the forefront of this challenge due to huge
population and also huge energy consumption.
y su enorme consumo de energía. population and also huge energy consumption.
Fast forward 10 years to today, so China has emerged as a
Avancemos 10 años hasta hoy, China se ha convertido en un Fast forward 10 years to today, so China has emerged as a
global leader in solar power deployment and it claimed the largest market
líder mundial en el despliegue de energía solar y ha reclamado el mercado más grande global leader in solar power deployment and it claimed the largest market
and for the battery-powered electric vehicles.
y el de los vehículos eléctricos con baterías. and for the battery-powered electric vehicles.
So committed to a decarbonized industrial upgrades, China has recognized hydrogen as
Comprometida con una actualización industrial descarbonizada, China ha reconocido el hidrógeno como So committed to a decarbonized industrial upgrades, China has recognized hydrogen as
an essential energy resource rather than hazardous chemicals.
un recurso energético esencial en lugar de productos químicos peligrosos. an essential energy resource rather than hazardous chemicals.
So this has been a significant shift that already noted in its
Este es un cambio significativo que ya se ha señalado en su So this has been a significant shift that already noted in its
national energy law draft of 2020.
proyecto de ley de energía nacional de 2020. national energy law draft of 2020.
So as announced also in the latest 14th five-year development plan,
Como se anunció también en el último plan quinquenal de la 14ª edición, So as announced also in the latest 14th five-year development plan,
China has taken extraordinary steps with substantial investment in clean hydrogen technologies
China ha tomado medidas extraordinarias con inversiones sustanciales en tecnologías de hidrógeno limpio China has taken extraordinary steps with substantial investment in clean hydrogen tech
to foster a sustainable hydrogen economy and also further to achieve its
para fomentar una economía de hidrógeno sostenible y, además, para lograr su to foster a sustainable hydrogen economy and also further to achieve its
commitment to carbon neutrality by 2016.
compromiso con la neutralidad de carbono para 2016. commitment to carbon neutrality by 2016.
So across the continents, another chapter unfolds.
A través de los continentes, se está desplegando otro capítulo. So across the continents, another chapter unfolds.
Europe is renowned for its long-term commitment in sustainability and tremendous
Europa es conocida por su compromiso a largo plazo con la sostenibilidad y sus grandes acciones Europe is renowned for its long-term commitment in sustainability and tremendous
actions in climate change.
contra el cambio climático. actions in climate change.
And also Europe indeed has embraced clean energy technologies wholeheartedly since last
Y Europa de hecho ha adoptado tecnologías de energía limpia con todo su corazón desde el siglo pasado. And also Europe indeed has embraced clean energy technologies wholeheartedly since last
century.
siglo. century.
Ambitious initiatives like European Clean Hydrogen Alliance and also the Repower EU
Iniciativas ambiciosas como la Alianza Europea para el Hidrógeno Limpio y también el Plan Repower EU Ambitious initiatives like European Clean Hydrogen Alliance and also the Repower EU
plan are fueling innovation and fostering global collaboration.
están impulsando la innovación y fomentando la colaboración global. plan are fueling innovation and fostering global collaboration.
The European Hydrogen Bank announced by the European Union in 2022 with
El Banco Europeo de Hidrógeno anunciado por la Unión Europea en 2022 con The European Hydrogen Bank announced by the European Union in 2022 with
an initial funding of 3 billion euros.
un financiamiento inicial de 3 mil millones de euros. an initial funding of 3 billion euros.
So the bank aims to boost the European hydrogen market to a
El banco tiene como objetivo impulsar el mercado europeo de hidrógeno a un So the bank aims to boost the European hydrogen market to a
brand new level.
nuevo nivel. brand new level.
Nations like Germany, Netherlands and France, they are also making significant investment
Países como Alemania, Países Bajos y Francia, también están realizando inversiones significativas Nations like Germany, Netherlands and France, they are also making significant investment
in hydrogen infrastructure, pushing the boundaries of clean energy adoption.
en infraestructura de hidrógeno, empujando los límites de la adopción de energías limpias. in hydrogen infrastructure, pushing the boundaries of clean energy adoption.
Digital sustainability, the marriage of digitization and sustainability.
La sostenibilidad digital, la unión de la digitalización y la sostenibilidad. Digital sustainability, the marriage of digitization and sustainability.
So it holds immense promise for our journey towards a sustainable future.
Ofrece una inmensa promesa para nuestro camino hacia un futuro sostenible. So it holds immense promise for our journey towards a sustainable future.
The power of digital sustainability, such as a rising new star, everyone
El poder de la sostenibilidad digital, como una nueva estrella ascendente, todos The power of digital sustainability, such as a rising new star, everyone
knows, chatGBT, blockchain, artificial intelligence and the Internet of Things is revolutionizing
sabe, chatGBT, blockchain, inteligencia artificial e Internet de las Cosas knows, chatGBT, blockchain, artificial intelligence and the Internet of Things
how we produce, distribute and consume energy.
está revolucionando la forma en que producimos, distribuimos y consumimos energía. is revolutionizing how we produce, distribute and consume energy.
These technologies enable us to optimize energy systems, improve efficiency and enhance
Estas tecnologías nos permiten optimizar los sistemas energéticos, mejorar la eficiencia y These technologies enable us to optimize energy systems, improve efficiency and
the integration of renewable energy resources.
mejorar la integración de recursos energéticos renovables. enhance the integration of renewable energy resources.
Let's imagine a world where the energy systems are smart, interconnected and
Imaginemos un mundo donde los sistemas energéticos sean inteligentes, interconectados y reactivos. Let's imagine a world where the energy systems are smart, interconnected and responsive.
Buildings and cities become like energy hubs, generating and sharing electricity, heat
Los edificios y las ciudades se convierten en centros de energía, generando y compartiendo electricidad, calor Buildings and cities become like energy hubs, generating and sharing electricity, heat
and even hydrogen.
e incluso hidrógeno. and even hydrogen.
So renewable energy sources are seamlessly integrated into the grid, creating a
Las fuentes de energía renovables están perfectamente integradas en la red, creando una So renewable energy sources are seamlessly integrated into the grid, creating a
decentralized and resilient energy network.
red energética descentralizada y resiliente. decentralized and resilient energy network.
By embracing clean energy technologies such as hydrogen and leveraging the power
Al adoptar tecnologías de energía limpia como el hidrógeno y aprovechar el poder By embracing clean energy technologies such as hydrogen and leveraging the power
of digital sustainability, we process the tools already and to drive this
de la sostenibilidad digital, ya tenemos las herramientas necesarias para avanzar en esta transición. of digital sustainability, we process the tools already and to drive this transition forward.
So governments, industrial leaders and researchers, we must collaborate on a global
Los gobiernos, los líderes industriales y los investigadores, debemos colaborar en un escenario global So governments, industrial leaders and researchers, we must collaborate on a global
stage and to develop innovation solutions and forging a path towards a
y desarrollar soluciones innovadoras, forjando un camino hacia un stage and to develop innovation solutions and forging a path towards a
world powered by clean energy and driven by digital sustainability.
mundo alimentado por energía limpia y guiado por sostenibilidad digital. world powered by clean energy and driven by digital sustainability.
(End)
(Fin) (End)